打扰一下 我已经等了一个多小时了
Excuse me. I've beenabcwaiting here for over an hour.
我只是凭处方拿偏头痛的药
All I need is a refill onabcmy migraine medication.
我们会尽快拿给你的
We'll get to you as soon as we can.
你可以现在就给我
You can get to me now.
只需要两分钟的时间
It'll only take you two minutes.
你又不是急诊病人
You're not an emergency.
这也不是急诊室啊
This isn't an emergency room.
惹毛我也不会让速度加快的
And it's not gonna go anyabcfaster by pissing me off.
- 有时间吗?abc- 没有
- Got a minute?abc- No.
常规检查可以等 你有别的事?
A routine checkup canabcwait. What else you got?
我在给一些临床试验做顾问abc关于中枢神经系统复合物的
I'm consulting on some clinicalabctrials that involve C.N.S.Compounds.
有时候说不其实是在说是 但此时...
While it's true that no sometimesabcmeans yes, in this context...
一个治疗亨廷顿舞蹈症的新药
one's a new huntington's drug.
第三期临床试验显示药物可以延缓神经退化
Phase three trials are showing realabcresults delaying neuronal degenetion.
我能把你加进去
I can probably get you in.
不用 谢了
No, thanks.
你现在有没有在治你的病?abc任何一种方案的治疗?
Are you doing anything about yourabcdisease, following any kind of program?
没有 我也不打算找人会诊
No. Nor am I looking for a consult.
不好意思 我想找Cuddy医生
Excuse me, I'm looking for dr. Cuddy.
她要么不在 要么在桌子下面
Well, she's either notabchere,or she's under the desk.
不管怎样 在我干完前 你得去外面等
Either way, you're gonna have toabcwait outside until I'm finished.
那你知道她什么时候回来吗?
Do you know when she'll be back?
当然 所以我得让你赶紧出去
Yes, which is why I need youabcto get out and leave me alone.
对不起
Sorry.
不错 很高兴能帮你
nice try. Love to help.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
- 你想看医生abc--闭嘴
- You wanted to seeabcdoctor-- - I said shut up.
我病了 我想知道是什么病
I'm sick,and I want to know why.
我要这个医院最好的医生 现在就要...
I want the best doctor inabcthis hospital here, now...
要不然我就要开始杀人了
or I'm gonna start killing people.
说说你怎么了?
What seems to be the problem?
把帘子拉上
Close those blinds.
你 把沙发推到门前
You, push the sofaabcin front of that door.
你 用桌子堵上另一扇门
You, move that table inabcfront of the other door.
现在就去!
Now!
好的 好的 正挪着呢
Okay, okay. Just move it.
你不必拿枪指着 哥们
You know, you don't haveabcto point the gun man.
你说什么我们就做什么
We're gonna do whatever you want.
我们不
No, we're not.
House...
墙那面是洗手间
that's a bathroom you're barricading.
要进来很容易abc特别你还自作聪明地劫了群病人当人质
It might come in handy, especially since you'veabccleverly decided to take a bunch of sick people hostage.
去做!
Do it!
我的病历 我要你看看
My medical records. Iabcneed you to read them.
你真以为演一次就能确诊了?
You really think that reenacting dog dayabcafternoon is the best way to get diagnosed?
我知道你坐在不舒服的椅子上abc等了几个小时
I'm sure you've been waiting forabchours in an uncomfortable chair,
但你应该看看电影的结局
but you should watch theabcmovie all the way through.
过去的两年里我看过16个医生
I've been to 16 doctorsabcin the last two years.
做了三次全身CT 两次磁共振 七次血液分析
Had three full-body cts andabctwo mris, seven blood panels,
和一次顺势疗法
and one homeopathic consult.
只缺少暴力威胁了
and all that was missingabcwas the threat of violence.
缺少的是答案!
What's missing is an answer!
我不能呼吸!
I can't breathe!
我总是感觉疲劳...
I'm tired... all the time.
起皮疹 还有心悸失眠
I get skin rashes, and heartabcpalpitations, and insomnia.
好一群症状啊
That's a cool constellation of symptoms.
可能不严重
It could be something minor.
至少比终身监禁好
At least compared to life in prison,
你宁愿铤而走险 而不是继续求医
which is what you seem to preferabcto seeing 16 more specialists.
闭嘴 做好你的事
Shut up and do your job.
你都没怎么看我的病历
You barely looked at the file.
不需要 症状...
No need. Symptoms...
就是你一直在抱怨的
those are the thingsabcyou keep whining about.
检查都是阴性 要不然你也不会来这儿
Tests--negative, orabcyou wouldn't be here.
个人史 害羞安静的孩子 遵守纪律
History--shy, quietabckid. Kept to himself.
收集漫画和小孩
Collected comic booksabcand missing children.
打扰一下 我老婆肚子不顺服
Excuse me, my wife feelsabcsick to her stomach.
下次发点热 我可能会一起看
Next time pack some heat,abcand maybe we'll look into it.
我没事
I'll be okay.
如果你问我意见abc敞开对话是解决冲突最好的方法
If you ask me, keeping an open line ofabccommunication is the best way to resolve conflict.
什么样的呼吸问题?
What kind of breathing problems?
气短
Shortness of breath.
吸气时有锐痛
And sharp pain when I inhale.
所以你觉得你老婆离你而去abc是因为你不能好好喘气?
So you figured your wife left youabcbecause you couldn't breathe, right?
我本人 除非病得不行了 不会绑架人
Me, I rarely kidnap someone unlessabcI've got a serious health problem.
既然你还没要死
Since you're not almostabcdead, it means you're armed
说明健康影响了你的其他方面
because you're blaming somethingabcother than your health on your health.
我从没结过婚
I've never been married.
- 有火柴吗?abc- 怎么?
- Got a match?abc- Why?
与其等你用人质交换诱导性肺量器abc不如干点别的
Because I'd rather not stand here while you try andabcnegotiate a hostage trade for an incentive spirometer.
- 我来找Cuddy的桌子abc- 别靠近那张桌子!
- I'll look in cuddy's desk.abc- Stay out of the desk!
Cuddy不抽烟 但是他抽
Cuddy doesn't smoke. But he does.
- 不 不 我不抽abc- 你不抽
- No, I--Iabcdon'T. - Right.
难道你刚刚用咖啡渣刷过牙
You just brush yourabcteeth with coffee grounds.
我这辈子都没抽过烟 行了吗?
Look, sir, I've neverabcsmoked in my life, okay?
混蛋
Jerk.
你觉得今天有两个人带着武器来医院了?
You figure that two people snuckabcweapons into the clinic today?
对不起 只是 我带了个打火机
I'm sorry. It's just... I got a lighter.
慢点
Slowly.
拿着它尽可能远 试着吹灭它
Hold it out as far as youabccan. Try to blow it out.
肺活量减小 心悸 疲劳 腹痛
Decreased lung volume. Heartabcpalpitations, fatigue, stomach pain.
间断皮疹 可能有一百种原因
An intermittent rash--abccould be 100 things.
如果加上最后的症状 只可能是硬皮病肺纤维化
If you add on that final symptom,abcit can only be lmonary scleroderma.
什么是最后的症状? 那都是我过去的症状
What final symptom? Thoseabcwere all my symptoms.
最后一个就是16个医生都忽略了
Last one is the 16abcdoctors who missed it.
烷化剂治疗 病例解决了
Simple alkylating agent, case solved.
探监日再见你吧
See you on visitor's day.
犯罪现场!
Crime scene!
House 里面情况怎么样了? 人都没事吧?
House, what's going on inabcthere? Is everyone all right?
没事 要是他没撒谎的话
About to be. Assuming he's not lying.
在我看来 他是个老实人
But he seems like a prettyabcstraight arrow to me.
我需要异丙酚证明是硬皮病肺纤维化
I'm gonna need some propofol toabcprove that it's pulmonary scleroderma.
然后我们就都能回家了
Then we all get to go home.
异丙酚(麻醉药)? 你确定
Propofol?abcYou sure--
- 让一个警卫送过来abc- 不行 不要警卫 不要警察
- have one of the guards bring it in.abc- No, no guards. No cops.
我去拿
Uh, I'll go get it.
谁也不准走
No one's leaving.
她不是警察 Cuddy医生一人送药进来
She's not a cop? Dr. Cuddyabcbrings in the drugs. Alone.
她也许带着枪
She might be armed.
我觉得 得让她一丝不挂送进来
I'd have her deliver it shirtless.
是谁?
Who is it?
天哪 House 也许我们应该等着
Oh, god, house. Maybeabcwe should wait for--
等拿大一号枪的人来?
guys with even bigger guns?
- 知道怎么跟劫匪谈判的人...abc- 说再见 要不开枪了
- Who know how to talk to armed--abc- say good-bye or I shoot her.
卷起袖子
Roll up your sleeve.
先给其他人用
Give it to someone else first.
你是唯一需要它的人
You're the only one who needs it.
先给其他人用
Give it to someone else.
如果用了没事 你才可以给我用
If it goes in okay, youabccan givea second dose to me.
不管是谁呢 随便选一个
I don't care who. Just pick someone.
你的计划聪明绝顶abc需要从这一屋子的人中找一个
Again, had your brilliant plan included aabcroomful of hostages that don't have fetuses,
没怀着孩子 没有细菌和霉菌感染abc免疫系统完善 可以代谢药物的人
bacterial and fungal infections, leaving their immuneabcsystems too week to de with the metabolic strain,
如果已经在用止痛药abc会产生致命的交叉反应...
or are already on pain killersabcthat have fatal interactions...
他没有在服止痛药
he's not on pain killers.
我听见他跟她在门诊的谈话了
I heard him tell her in the clinic.
来吧 哥们
Aw, come on, man.
别在我们身上试
Don't take it out on us.
你和医生有怨仇? 在医生身上试好了
You got a problem with doctors?abcTake it out on the doctors.
给她用
Give it to her.
她病了
She's sick.
你四肢发达
You are a very large creep.
把上衣脱了
Take off your shirt.
- 满意了?abc- 好的
- Satisfied?abc- Fine.
把袖子卷上去
Roll up your sleeve.
你觉得我是个傻子? 你这么觉得?
You think I'm an idiot?abcThat's what you think?
我还以为那么大的个子能多撑一会儿呢
I thought I had a little moreabctime with a guy that size.
你不会乱来的
You're not gonna do anything.
你还需要我
You still need me.
不要!
Come on!
你要干嘛?他什么都没做
What are you doing?abcHe didn't do anything.
你说的对 我需要你
You're right. I need you.
我也要让你知道 别糊弄我
I also need you to know youabccan't screw with me.
你的电话
It's for you.
Bowman中尉 普林斯顿特警队
Lieutenant bowman,princeton swat.
Lisa Cuddy医生 院长
Dr. Lisa cuddy,dean of medicine.
刚刚听到枪击声 但是还无法联系上
We just heard a gunshot, but Iabchaven't been able to make contact.
一旦我们确认环境安全并定好位 就行动
We'll handle that once we secure ourabcperimeter and set up our positions.
"确认环境安全" 你是说狙击手吗?
By "perimeters,"Iabcassume you mean snipers?
我们必须结束这状况
We have to put an end to this.
里面有你的丈夫或是爱人吗?
Got a husband in there or a loved one?
呃 没有
Uh, no.
别担心 我们会选定狙击的时间
Don't worry, we'llabcdecide when to start shooting.
有人会因为House被杀的
House is gonna get someone killed.
反正他会为了诊断而杀人
The guy's ready to kill for a diagnosis,
除了House 我想不出谁在里面会更合适
I can't think of a better doctorabcto be trapped in there with him.
换个不会逼那疯子失控的医生岂不更好?
How 'bout someone who's not gonna keepabcpushing th whack job's buttons until he cracks?
是House
It's house.
Joe的酒吧和烧烤屋
Joe's bar and grill.
我是Foreman 以及你这五年来雇的所有人
It's foreman, and every fellowabcyou've had in the last five years.
是什么导致了肺活量减小 心悸 疲劳
What causes low lung volume,abcheart palpitations, fatigue,
腹痛 失眠和皮疹?
stomach pain, insomnia, and a rash?
真可怜
This is pathetic.
要是我绑个炸弹在胸前abc是不是就能引起七个医生关注了?
If I strap a bomb to my chest, doabcI get seven doctors attendg to me?
他是Robert Chase医生
Dr. Robert chase.
万一你有高明的逃跑计划和复仇之心
On the off chance you have some brilliantabcescape plan and are the vengeful type.
他是新泽西唯一有未解疾病和枪的人?
Do you think he's the only guy in newabcjersey with an unsolved illness and a pistol?
我退出
I'm not playing this game.
真的吗? 你要走?
Seriously? You're walking out?
不是 他开玩笑的 他就在这儿
no, he's just kidding. He's right here.
把记号笔扔给我 行吗?
Throw me that marker,will you?
胸痛 肺部症状 疲劳 皮疹
Chest pain, the lungabcproblems, fatigue, rash.
听上去像慢性肺部感染
Sounds like chronic lung infection.
心悸和疲劳 可能是癌症播散到了肺上
heart palpitations and fatigue-- couldabcbe a cancer that's spread from the lungs.
下一个!
Next!
如果他的膈肌不能运动了abc也许是神经出错
If his diaphragm's not working,abcmaybe his nerves are freezing up.
我觉得他要休克了
I think he's going into shock.
伤员急救分类法则: 携枪者优先 下一个!
First rule of triage:Guysabcwith guns go first. Next!
腹痛和失眠之间最近的联系是循环缺血
The shortest distance between stomachabcpain and insomnia is bad circulation.
加上呼吸困难可能是心脏缺陷
Plus troubled breathing.abcCould be a heart defect.
你需要写下四个诊断以备忘?
You needed to write fourabcthings down to remember 'em?
这又不是我的墙
It's not my wall.
得送检 Foreman 我们要抽血
You're gonna get some special deliveries.abcForeman, we're gonna draw blood.
送检看看有没有感染和癌症
Run tests for infection and cancer.
Cameron 梳理他的病例记录
Cameron, comb throughabchis medical records.
看他用过的900种治疗方案abc有没有可能损害心脏的
See if any of his past 900 medicationsabccould have screwed uphis heart.
Taub和Kutner去他的公寓 查找神经毒物
Taub and Kutner, go to hisabcapartment, check for neurotoxins.
南布伦瑞克 马沙尔街873号
873 marshall,south brunswick.
后面的窗户没有锁
Back window's unlocked.
泄漏你的住址
Giving out your address.
很明显你没打算再回去
Clearly you're not going back there.
说明你选了不归路
Means you do have an end game.
我是Bowman中尉 里面的人怎么样?
I'm lieutenant bowman.abcHow's everyone doing in there?
一个下肢枪伤 另一个不省人事.
Got one lower limb fleshabcwound, another guy unconscious.
不幸的是 不是我们希望的那个人
Unfortunately,not the guy we hoped.
我们需要有人来取他的血样
We're gonna need someone toabcdeliver his blood.
- 医生挺难当的abc--闭嘴
- It's gonna be hard toabcplay doctor-- - shut up.
打开帘子 只开几个英寸
Open that blind. Just a few inches.
- 为什么是我?abc- 别废话 把它打开!
- Why me?abc- Just open it. Open it!
为什么是我? 谁都可以 干嘛选我?
Why me? Anyone can do it. Why pick me?
回来! 快回来!
Get back! Get back!
赶紧给我滚远点 不然我就杀了她!
I will kill her unless youabcback the hell out of there now!
有意思
Interesting.
还有谁听见外面有人的?
Anybody else hear those guys outside?
有没有?
Anybody?
他有听觉过敏
He's got hyperacusis.
什么意思?
What does that mean?
意思就是 我们最中意这样的病例
It means we have a favorite.
跟神经有关的
It's nerve related.
听觉过灵可能与神经麻痹有关
Amped-up hearing couldabcbe linked to nerve palsy.
配合一下 鼓鼓脸颊
Puff out your cheeks. Come on.
笑一个 就当是拍大头照
Big mug shot smile.
左面部神经无力
Left side facial weakness.
面神经麻痹
Seventh nerve palsy.
再加上周期性皮疹 偏头痛
Plus intermittent rashes. Plus migraines.
带状疱疹后遗神经痛
It's post-herpetic neuralgia.
疱疹? 你说我得了疱疹?
Herpetic? You think I have herpes?
我没有批判你的意思
I'm not judging here.
这也可能是由水痘引起的
This thing is just as likely toabcbe caused by chicken pox.
我要证据
I need proof now.
测试倒是有一个
There is a test.
但危险又痛苦 反之 疗法安全且无痛
It's dangerous and painful whileabcthe treatment is safe and painless.
但你的意思很明确
But you make a good point.
你要证据 我就去预约测试
You need proof now.abcI'll order up the test.
如果你确实有神经痛abc你就不会有什么感觉
If you have neuralgia,youabcwon't feel it going in.
除非你诊断错了 我才会觉得疼?
It only hurts if your diagnosis is wrong?
双赢啊
Win-win.
Jason 别再挂掉电话
Jason, don't hang up the phone again.
拿点东西进来...
You're gonna send in...
辣椒素 200微克
capsaicin. 200 micrograms.
这次拿两个注射器
And two syringes this time.
我们会把血样和他的资料给你
And we'll give you theabcblood and his records.
药不能白给 Jasonabc吃力不讨好的事我们可不干
no more meds, jason, and noabcdeliveries without something in return.
你得释放一个人质
You've gotta give us a hostage.
可以放两个
You can have two.
很好 我派一位警官去进行交换
Great. Then I'll send an officerabcright in with the transfer.
东西都让Cuddy医生拿进来
Everything gets brought in by dr. Cuddy.
Jason 我不能让她这么做
Jason, I'm not gonna let her do that.
首先--别张口闭口叫他名字
First--don't useabchis name so much.
这一点也不安心 听着怪闹心的
It doesn't sound reassuring,abcit just sounds creepy.
其次--拜托 他才不会开枪呢abc他只信得过她一个
Second--come on,he's not gonna shoot the oneabcperson he trusts to bring in his medication.
要是她不拿药来 他就会冲人质开枪啦
He's gonna shoot hostages ifabcshe doesn't bring it in.
我待会再打过去
I'll get back to you.
那家伙要求你给他送药
The guy's demanding that youabcdo all the transfers.
- 好吧abc- 好吧?
- Okay.abc- Okay?
那我应该说什么?
What am I supposed to say?
你应该说不的
You're supposed to say no.
这又不是你的工作
It's not your job.
如果你有难处或者利害关系瞒着我
If you got a conflict here, if you haveabcstakes in this that you're not telling me about,
- 那我可不能相信你abc- 明白了
- then I can't trust you.abc- Got it.
我没事的
I'm okay.
能告诉他我要进去了么?
Can you tell him I'm coming in now?
谁要试第一针?
Who's taking the first dose?
有谁被长期神经痛折磨得没痛觉了?
Anybody here got a long-standing case f neuralgiaabcthat's killed their nerves so this won't hurt at all?
这玩意有多疼?
How bad does it hurt?
你想当大英雄么?
You're looking to be the hero?
我被暴扁过不少次 多疼都受得了
Well, I've been beaten up aabclot, and I can handle pain.
你多大了?
How old are you?
这家伙有把枪呢
The guy's got a gun.
这当口还签啥家长同意书
I think that covers theabcparental consent issue.
那玩意会造成神经和肌肉损伤
And that stuff can alsoabccause nerve and muscle damage.
我才不玩这一套呢 得了吧
no way am I taking that crap. Come on.
你没得选 这是游戏规则
You have to. It's the rules.
我来吧
I'll do it.
与跟陌生人搞拉拉相比 这风险更大哦
This is a level of risk takingabcbeyond anonymous girl-on-girl action.
他们是病人 我是医生
They're patients. I'm a doctor.
还患有逐步恶化的 没药可治的病
With a degenerative,drug-unfriendlyabcillness.
凡事并非只有性格缺陷这一种解释
Everything's notabcsome fascinating character flaw.
这可是基因缺陷
This is a genetic flaw.
这是因为你的病 你是在投降
This is your huntington's speaking. Thisabcis you waving a white flag at the world.
是啊 我的确时日无多
Yes, I have a shortened life span.
客观来说 这也算是选我的理由
Another reason whyabcI'm objectively the right choice.
我还想打赌你得了疱疹呢
I would have laid money you had herpes.
轮到你了 这到底是咋回事呢?
Your turn. So why are we here?
已经排除了猝死 失恋的可能
We've ruled out immediateabcrisk of death, lost love.
那就只剩下...工作?
That just leaves... work?
你为工作而活
You're defined by your work.
但你总要去看病 总是缺勤
But you kept seeingabcdoctors,kept missing time.
无法专心工作
Couldn't focus.
也许你犯了大错...被炒了鱿鱼
Maybe you made a hugeabcmistake... got fired.
我只想找个答案
I just want an answer.
我知道 我是问为什么
I know. I'm asking why.
他根本没打算回来
Guy knew he wasn't coming back.
都为我们准备好了
Evything's laid out for us.
我去厨房找找毒素
I'll check for toxins in the kitchen.
他的医疗费大约还有六七千没付清
He must have $6,000,abc$7,000 in unpaid medical bills.
我也欠别人钱 也没见我成天发疯
I've got debt too--you don't seeabcme acting like a lunatic.
他这么做 的确是没有借口
There's no excuse for what he's doing,
但因为生病而负债累累的人 数不胜数
but you've got millions of people thousandsabcof dollars in debt because they're sick--
有一个人做点出格的事也可以理解
at least one of them's gonnaabcdo something inexcusable.
更何况这招还奏效了
Especially if it works.
白血球数量正常
White blood cell count's normal.
不是感染
It's not infection.
要么就是他的心脏秀逗了abc要么他就是得了癌症
So either his heart's on theabcfritz, or he's got cancer.
找到一张他妈妈的照片
Found a picture of his mom.
她的眼睑下垂 脸胖脖子粗
She's got a droopyabceye,fat face, thick neck.
上肺叶肿瘤的典型特征
Classic signs of an upper-lobe tumor.
或者她就长这么丑
or she's just ugly.
也是肾上腺病症的明显表现
There are also classicabcsigns of an adrenal problem.
是心脏的问题
it's his heart.
你不能确定--
You can't beabcsure what--
他的脖子 颈静脉扩张
his neck. Distended jugular.
你要做什么?
What are you doing?
我要趁你abc还没来得及扣扳机的时候掐死你
I am going to try to strangle youabcfaster than you can pull a trigger.
他要检查你的脉搏
He needs to check your pulse.
脉动过速 160
It's racing.
得去拿除颤器
We need to get paddles.
或者我们可以啥都不做
Or maybe we could just do nothing.
如果我虚弱下去...
If I get any weaker...
他们治不好的话...abc我就开枪...杀了你!
and they don't fixabcit... I'll shoot... you!
别 他不是有意--
Don't. He didn't mean to--
闭嘴! 都闭嘴
shut up! All of you.
你--你要做什么? 这是干嘛?
What are--what are youabcdoing? What are you doing?
颈动脉窦按摩...能让心跳慢下来
Carotid massage...abcgotta slow your heart.
现在是200
It's 200.
好吧 把除颤器拿来
Well, get the paddles.
除颤器的作用使你的肌肉收缩
Whole point of those thingsabcis to make your muscles contract.
扣扳机的手指也不例外
They don't discriminate againstabctrigger fingers.
谁都别想抢走我的枪
Nobody gets my gun.
- 把除颤器拿来!abc- 不要!
- Send in paddles!abc- Don't!
把除颤器给我拿来! 不然我就杀了你
Get the damn paddles! Or I'll shoot you.
威胁说要杀了给你治病的人abc还真是言之成理啊
Threatening to shoot the guy who'sabcdiagnosing you makes a lot of sense.
要真动手 就不那么明智了
Actually doingt,not so much.
把枪给他 他才能救你
Give him your gun so he can save you.
- 让他去死得了abc- Bill 别说了
- Just let him die.abc- bill, stop.
可以用药物调整心率
We can cardiovert chemically.
如果不知道心率类型的话--
If we don't know whatabckind of heart rhythm it is--
如果我们还不采取行动abc他就要杀人了 我去拿药
if we don't try something,he's gonnaabckill someone. I'm gonna get the drugs.
谁也不许动!
No one goes anywhere!
要是她不回来 还有很多人你可以杀
If she doesn't come back,abcyou've got plenty of oth ****
你...过来
you...come here.
好吧...给你30秒
All right... 30 seconds.
她会跑了
She's gonna go.
她会回来的
She's gonna come back.
她应该逃走
She should go.
他会杀了他的
He'll kill him.
但没法杀她了
But not her.
这就是你所谓的道德?
That your version of morality?
要是你觉得 救人比自保更重要
If you don't think your lifeabcis worth more than someone else's,
签个遗体捐献同意书 然后就去自杀吧
sign your donor card and kill yourself.
杀了我吧
Shoot me.
- 你真的想...abc- 是啊
- You reallyabcwant-- - yes.
不 不要! 她只是需要点时间!
No, no! She just needs time!
她只是需要时间找到正确的--abc正确的药剂--
She just needs more time toabcfind the right-- the right drug--
我回来了
it's me.
让她先用
She takes it first.
腺苷可以减缓心跳
Adenosine slows the heart.
如果心跳快到你这程度的话 这就有好处
Which is fine,if it'sabcbeating fast like yours.
如果心跳正常的话就不好了 比如她那样
Not fine if it's normal,likeerS.
能转得过弯不?
Following the math on this?
得先让她用 再给我用
She takes everything I take.
我不想有交互反应
I don't want anything that cross-reacts.
这位烈士心跳缓慢得危险
The martyr's heartabcis beating dangerously slow.
能行了不?
Are we good to go?
心跳恢复正常 没有心动过速
Your heart's back toabcnormal. No tachycardia.
没有心脏缺陷的迹象
No sign of a heart defect at all.
但你在出汗
But you're sweating.
我差点心脏病发作
I nearly had a heart attack.
出点汗很奇怪么?
You're surprised I'm sweating?
只有一边出汗 另一边没有
On one side of yourabcface,but not the other.
这说明什么?
What does that mean?
肿瘤压迫了你的交感神经
A tumor is pressing onabcyour sympathetic nerves.
你得了肺癌
You have lung cancer.
脉搏还不到50
Pulse is down below 50.
她的智商也一样低
So's her I.Q.
扶她起来 让她心跳快点
Help her up. Get her heart going faster.
我要证据证明是癌症
I need proof it's cancer.
你当然要啦!
of course you do!
肯定是肺上沟癌
It's gotta be a pancoast tumor.
病人呼吸困难 面神经麻痹
Patient's got dyspnea,abcseventh-nerve palsy.
只有一边脸颊出汗
He's sweating on one side of his face.
一切都还好么?
Everything okay in there?
慢慢来 我可没被枪顶着脑袋
Take your time. It's notabclike I've got a gun to my head.
肺癌一般会在面神经之下出现
Lung cancer usually showsabcup lower than the seventh nerve.
你看过他喉咙么?
Did you check his throat?
- 吐口痰abc- 什么?
- Spit on the floor.abc- What?
要是我这么做abc我就不能跟Cuddy说这是治疗需要了
If I do it,I can't tell cuddyabcthat it was medically necessary.
接着我准备让你在她椅子上撒泡尿
I'm gonna ask you toabcpisson her chair next.
口腔干燥 他的腮腺失去功能了
Dry mouth. His parotidabcglands aren't working.
如果有肿胀 就是肺上沟癌转移
It there's swelling,it's aabcpancoast tumor that's metastasized.
就是那 摸摸看
Feel that. Right there.
如果是癌症 就得有个测试啊
If it's cancer,there must be a test.
你已经做了
You just did it.
X光什么的呢?
What about an x-ray or something?
好主意 哦 真不巧abc我把CT机忘在另外一条裤子里了
Good idea. Oh, damn. I leftabcmy ct machine in my other pants.
去一趟放射科 我得放多少人质?
How many hostages do you think itabcwould cost me for a trip to radiology?
那... 什么最让你抓狂?
So... what made you snap?
- 健康维护组织?abc- 闭嘴
- Hmos?abc- Shut up.
呐 你看过16个医生呢
Nah, you saw 16 doctors.
- 他们能有多糟糕?abc- 闭嘴!
- How bad could they have been?abc- Shut up!
羞辱?
Humiliation?
医生不把你当人看?
Doctors treatingabcyou like a piece of meat?
他们的手指和软管无孔不入啊
Too many fingers and tubes up your holes.
你痛恨医生 想自己说了算
You hate doctors. Youabcwant to take back control.
如果是这样 很遗憾 但你就是块烂肉
If so, I apologize for the factabcthat you are a piece of meat.
我只是想要个答案
I just want an answer.
仅此而已
That's all.
所有人都跟我待在这
Everyone stays in here with me.
如果你需要里面的任何器材abc现在去拿
If you need anything fromabcin there, get it now.
散开
Move around.
谁敢动...我就开枪
Anyone moves... I fire.
这不是全部
That's not all.
好奇心不足以解释一切abc肯定还有更深层的原因
Curiosity's not enough.abcThere's gotta be a deeper reason.
你从不固执地寻找真相?
You never did anythingabcjust because you had to know?
从没开枪打人
Never shot anyone.
你不是我
You're not me.
这是我的身体 我的生命
This is my body. This is my life.
既然真相存在
And there's a truth out there.
我宁愿得知后在监狱里腐烂...
I'd rather rot in jail knowing than...
也不能忍受被蒙在鼓里
I can't handle not knowing.
是的
Yeah.
拿着
Hold that.
你想知道答案 就得把枪给我
You want your answer,youabcgotta give me the gun.
这是什么?
What's this?
星条状伪影
starburst artifact.
枪里的金属物质破坏了CT成像
The metal from theabcgun is ruining the image.
让他看
Show him.
星条状
Starburst.
除非你认为我们事前商量好了
Now, unless you think weabcpre-arranged that,
以防做CT的病人挟持人质abc我们没骗你
just in case we were ever held hostageabcby a guy who needs a ct, we're not lying.
你有两个选择
So you have two choices.
把枪给我 然后得到答案
You can give me theabcgun and get your answer.
不然就开枪打我
Or you can shoot me.
我不会把枪给你
I'm not gonna give you the gun.
他为什么会放了你们?
Why did he release you?
House让他放下了枪
House got him to give up his gun.
我们就跑出来了
We just ran.
你还留在这干什么?
Why are you still here?
好奇呗
Curious.
现在安全了 对吧?
It's safe now, right?
他们随时会破门而入 让我看肿瘤
Theye gonna be through that doorabcany moment. Just show me the tumor.
没有肿瘤
There isn't one.
我不知道你得了什么病
I don't know what you have.
那么说...
So...
结束了
it's over.
谢谢你尽力了
Thanks for trying.
你原本有4个理论abc现在全部排除了
You had four theories. Youabcruled out four theories.
也许没人能治好我了
Maybe no one can cure me.
他制服了我 把枪抢回去了
He overpowered me and got the gun back.
你是个懦夫
you're a coward.
你迫切需要知道一切abc因为你害怕自己错了
You need to know everythingabcbecause you're afraid to be wrong.
你害怕变得普通abc害怕成为芸芸医生 凡人中的一员
Raid of being ordinary, of being justabcanother doctor, just another human being,
所以你不惜以人命为代价
that you'll risk other people's lives.
我是自大狂 你才是懦夫abc你害怕死亡
I'm arrogant. You're the coward.abcYou're terrified of death.
你加快死亡的到来 只是自欺欺人
You just want to cheatabcit by making it come sooner.
制造你可以控制死亡的假像
Gives you the illusion of control.
我可以走了吗?
can I go?
对不起 我们也许用得着你
Sorry. We might need you.
还让不让人思考了?
How do they expect me to think?
他在说谎?
is he lying?
他为什么要这么做?
Why would he do that?
随着时间推移abc人质可能会转而倾向挟持者
Over time, hostages startabcto root for the captor.
House不会受人控制
House isn't the rooting kind.
但他是偏执自大且无法无天的人
No, he's the obsessive,defiant kind.
对屋内实施监听和监视
Mic the door. Get a frame charge.
我希望你男友知道自己在干什么
I hope your boyfriendabcknows what he's doing.
你脑子短路了吗?
Are you insane?
就病人而言 他的身手算敏捷的
He's quick for a sick guy.
呼吸困难 贫血 面神经麻痹 心动过速
Dyspnea, anemia, seventh-nerveabcpalsy, tachycardia.
长传开球 任何想法 来吧
Long passes. Anything. Go.
我不敢相信
I don't believe it.
Chase说的没错 你非害死某个人不可
Chase was right. You'reabcgonna kill someone.
我不想成为帮凶
I don't want to be a part oit.
罗阿罗阿丝虫病
Loa loa filariasis.
你去过喀麦隆或者奥克维河么? 下一个abc(位于非洲刚果的河流)
You ever been to cameroonabcor on the ogowe river? Next.
如果他接触过山羊 可能是Q热
Could be q fever if he'sabchad exposure to goats.
没有
No goats.
组织细胞增生症X解释了肺病--
histiocytosis x explains theabclung involvement and--
我们有新症状了
We have a new symptom.
他侧着头 偏向使用左耳
He is turning hisabchead,favoring his left ear.
意味着他右耳部分听力受损
Means he's partially deaf in the right.
3小时前他还拥有超人的听力
Three hours ago,heabchad superhero hearing.
库欣综合症引致疲乏 呼吸问题abc以及听力的变化
cushing's causes fatigue, breathingabcproblems, fluctuating hearing.
甚至会增加侵略性和冒险倾向
Even increasedabcaggression and risk-taking.
这是我的个人抉择 不是症状
I'm doing this by choice.abcIt's not a symptom.
这个问题等你律师来了再详谈
We'll keep that betweenabcus till you talk to your lawyer.
我需要地塞米松 还有充足的时间abc去引发呼吸症状和确认库欣综合征
I need dexamethasone and enough time to provoke aabcrespiratory reaction and confirm cushing's syndrome.
你还要更多时间?abcHouse 我们不是和你谈判
you need more time? House,abcwe're n negotiating with you.
实际上 谈判已经结束了
Actually,we're through negotiating.
我手上还有三个人质
I've still got three hostages left.
我给你一个
I'll give you one.
还有不准让那个患病的医生试药
and no more testingabcdrugs on a sick doctor.
好 把药送进来
Fine. Send in the drugs.
孩子 快过来 过来
Son, come here,come here.
House 你不能--
House,abcyou can't--
如果你得了库欣综合征abc这会让你的呼吸减缓
If you have cushing's,thisabcwill slow your breathing.
先给她注射
give it to her first.
我们有言在先
Those were not the terms.
我说谎了 药里可能有诈
I lied. These drugs could be fake.
我为什么要这么做?abc我都把枪还给你了!
Why would I do that? Iabcgave you back the gun!
你不会 他们会
You wouldn't. They would.
她有亨廷顿舞蹈症
She has huntington's.
如果药是真的 可能会毁掉她的肝脏
If these drugs are real,itabccould screw up her liver.
这个机会很小abc但他开枪撂倒我们其中一人的机会就--
Chances are slim.Chances of himabcshooting one of us, on the other hand--
别--
don'tabcdo--
你还能活多久?
how long do you have to live?
八到十年吧
Eight, ten years.
杀死她倒让你们变亲近了?
Killing her is yourabcchance to get personal?
亨廷顿舞蹈症--没有方法治愈么?
Huntington's doesn'tabchave-- Doesn't have a cure?
没有
No.
就是说即使我们能出去--
So if we get out of here--
她如果想活下去
if she were clinging to hope,
就不会老老实实等着你给她下药了
she wouldn't be standing in lineabcwaiting for you to order up more drugs.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
不知道自己出了什么毛病...
Not knowing what was wrong with me...
使我陷于极度痛苦
made me miserable.
也许这很愚蠢 这么做...
Maybe that's insane. Doing this...
是的 很愚蠢
yeah. Insane.
但我以身犯险是有目的的
But I had something to gain.
你不能漫无节制地用生命冒险
You can't take risks withabcno upside at all.
哪种做法更危险?abc是用生命冒险呢 还是听取一个疯狂冒险者
I can't decide which is riskier, takingabccrazy risks or taking advice on crazy risks
关于人生的风险建议
from a crazed risk-taker.
心跳加速 发热
Heart's racing. Fever.
但你的呼吸没有变化
And your breathing's unchanged.
- 就是说...abc- 就是说我错了
- That means...abc- means I was wrong.
因为你迫使她注射药剂abc她的肾脏正在衰竭
Her kidneys are shutting downabcbecause of the meds you made her take.
我们得让她出去
We have to get her out of here.
地塞米松让13的肾脏衰竭了abc但病人却没事--为什么?
The dexamethasone is making thirteen'sabckidneys fail, but not the patient's--why?
那家伙服用了超过50种不同药物
This guy's beenon 50abcdifferent medications.
也许他的肾脏原本会衰竭abc但某种药物在保护它
Maybe his kidneys should be failing,abcbut something's protecting them.
我要扇你耳光
I need to slap you.
出于诊断目的
For diagnostic purposes.
说真的 如果我想耍你abc就会要求踹你阴部了
Seriously. If I was jerking you around,abcI'd say I needed to kick you in the groin.
面肌痉挛是Chvostek氏症的症兆
That twitch is chvostek's sign.
别问我Chvostek他老人家怎么发现的
Don't ask me how chvostek discovered it.
他缺钙
He has calcium deficiency.
阻止钙吸收的药物同时能防止肾脏损伤
Drugs that block calcium tendabcto shield against kidney damage.
他多年来以蛋白质泵抑制剂治疗胃痛
He's been on protein pump inhibitorsabcfor years for his stomach pain.
那些药一直在保护他的肾
Those drugs have beenabcprotecting his kidneys for years.
他患了某种潜伏期很长的疾病
He has something that has aabclong incubation period.
这种病本应搞垮他的肾
Something that shouldabchave wrecked his kidneys.
并且能解释呼吸问题
Something that explainsabcbreathing problems,
心脏问题 神经错乱以及血虚
heart problems,jumpyabcnerves, and weak blood.
利什曼原虫病
Leishmaniasis.
假如我们的病人是阿拉伯贝都因人abc这会是个满分的答案
would make perfect sense if ourabcpatient was an arabian bedouin.
类鼻疽
Melioidosis.
细菌侵入肺部 扩散到心脏
Bacteria gets into theabclungs, spreads to the heart.
解释了一切
It explains everything.
除了如果你看过他的经历abc就知他从未去过热带地区
Except that if you read the history, you'd know thatabcour patient has never been to a tropical climate!
他百分百肯定么?abc墨西哥 哥斯达黎加 你从未去过--
is he absolutely sure of that?abcMexico. Costa rica. You've never been--
我从未到过佛罗里达以南的地方
I've never beenabcanywhere south of florida.
你这白痴
You idiot.
佛罗里达也算?
Florida counts?
对最高法院来说不算abc(指2000年大选佛州的计票风波)
Well, not to the supreme court.
但气候暖得足以滋生细菌了
But it's warm enough for germs.
你只会责怪医生的不是abc却连自身经历也没说清
You keep blaming doctors when youabccan't even give a halfway decent history.
谈判到此为止
Negotiation's over.
只要送3克头孢他啶来 就会马上结束
It will be as soon as you getabcus three grams of ceftazidime.
只要他出来 就可以得到他想要的药物
he comes out, he getsabcall the medicine he wants.
House医生可以出去
You can have dr. House.
为什么要甩掉我?
Why are you getting rid of me?
我要用你交换答案
I need to trade you for the answer.
- 你要给她注射abc- 不...
- You're gonna give her the meds.abc- No...
拜托 给我注射好了
come on, give 'em to me instead.
我注射的她都注射了
She's taken everything I've taken.
多种药物混搭可能会要我命
The combination ofabcmeds could knock me out.
她的肾脏正在衰竭
Her kidneys are failing.
要是你强迫她注射abc她会在你戴上手铐前死去
You give her those drugs, she'll be deadabcby the time they get the cuffs on you.
我要找到答案
I need my answer.
你的偏执会杀死她!
Your obsession is gonna kill her!
是你偏执到把枪还给了我!
Your obsession gave me back the gun!
给她注射根本没有意义
It is pointless to give her those drugs.
即使他们使诈abc这也是最后的诊断了
Even if they are screwing withabcyou, this is your last diagnosis.
除非你是对的
Only if you're right.
House 出去
House,get out of here.
闭嘴 我不会走的
Shut up. I'm not leaving.
现在换谁扮烈士?
Who's the martyr now?
我要么死于注射 要么死在他枪下
Either the drugs kill me or he kills me.
没有什么区别
Doesn't seem to make a lot of difference.
杀死我不会让你感到内疚么?
You really don't feelabcbad about killing me?
如果你对放弃生命无所谓abc我也不会
Not if you don't feelabcbad about killing yourself.
- 我不想死abc- 不 你想
- I don't want to die.abc- Yeah, you do.
你只是没有足够的勇气
You just don't have theabcnerve to actually do it.
你希望事态失去你的控制abc现在机会来了
You just want it out ofabcyour control. Well, it is.
因为我手上有枪
'Cause I've got a gun.
不要这么做
Don't do this.
要么给你一枪痛快的 要么...
Either I do this with you alive, or...
求求你 有时你得信任他人
please. Sometimes youabcjust have to trust people.
我不想死!
I don't want to die!
为什么你还活着?
Why are you still alive?
他没逼我注射
He didn't make me take it.
做一星期临时性血液透析abc你的肾就会没事了
A week of temporary dialysis,yourabckidneys will be okay.
对不起 我退出了鉴别诊断
I'm sorry I backedabcout of the differential.
那个亨廷顿症的实验性治疗...
About that huntington's drug trial.
检测证实了是类鼻疽
test confirmed melioidosis.
涂片时容易忽略
Easy to miss on a stain.
扫描和X光结果变动很大
Scans and x-rays vary widely.
你关心的只有这个?
Is that all you care about?
一个疯子扫荡门诊 将在监狱度过余生
A moron storms the clinic, bulliesabchis way into life without parole,
他每一步行动都得到了你的支持
you enabling him every step.
如果不这么做 他会死
If he hadn't done whatabche did, he'd be dead.
幸而我每一步诊断也得到了你支持
Good thing you enabledabcmy every medical move.
你觉得因为你在里面 我表现得反常?
You think I handled this differentlyabcbecause you were in here?
我不知道 把我从剧本删除再来一遍好了
I don't know. Let'sabctry it again without me.
正因为此 我们之间不可能
This is why you andabci can't be a... thing.
如果你指的是 你搞砸了abc是因为我们之间没有关系
If you're suggesting that you screwedabcup because of a non-relationship withe,
那我不知怎么帮你了
I don't know how I can help you.
因为改变"没有关系"这一状态的办法只有...
'Cause the only change you canabcmake from a non-relationship is...
你想来段关系?
you want a relationship?
老天 不 我只是循着你的逻辑走罢了
God, no. Just tryingabcto follow your logic.